Guide to the Stanford University, Food Research Institute, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Food Research Institute, records
1916-1990
SC0570
Stanford University. Food Research Institute
40 Linear feet
Records include correspondence of William O. Jones and others, 1960s-80s; grant files; departmental files, 1920s-70s; funding records; photographs; and other materials, including two passports of Alonzo E. Taylor, 1916-17.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: personnel files are not available to researchers.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Food Research Institute at Stanford was founded in 1921 for the study of worldwide problems of food supply, distribution, and consumption. William O. Jones was its executive secretary from 1955 to 1962 and became the Director in 1964. The Institute was closed in June 1998.
Description of the Collection
Records include correspondence of William O. Jones and others, 1960s-80s; grant files; departmental files, 1920s-70s; funding records; photographs; and other materials, including two passports of Alonzo E. Taylor, 1916-17.
Access Terms
Jones, William O.; Stanford University. Food Research Institute; Taylor, Alonzo Englebert, 1871-1949.; Food--Research.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Correspondence 1960s - 1970s (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1970s (Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1980s (Box 3)
  - Correspondence 1980s (Box 4)
  - Contract and grant files (Box 5)
  - Contract and grant files (Box 6)
  - Correspondence files of William O. Jones: A - FRI Inst. Committee (Box 6)
  - Correspondence files of William O. Jones: FRI Inst. Committee - Mai (Box 7)
  - Correspondence files of William O. Jones: Mar - Smith (Box 8)
  - Correspondence 1980s (Box 9)
  - Correspondence 1980s (Box 10)
  - Project files (Box 11)
  - Foundation files (Box 11)
  - General alpha files A - H (Box 11)
  - General alpha files J - Z (Box 12)
  - Grant files 1945-46 (incl. Rockefeller funding) (Box 13)
  - Cassel manuscript: "Food and Recovery After World War II" (Box 13)
  - Memorial resolution on Wm. O. Jones (Box 14)
  - Photographs for 1970 FRI brochure (Box 14)
  - Correspondence files of Wm. O. Jones and Bruce F. Johnston re 50th Anniversary conference (1971) and other conference files (Box 14)
  - Departmental files, assorted (Box 14)
  - Visiting Scholar files: chronological (Box 14)
  - Visiting Scholar files: A - Z (Box 15)
  - Grant files (Box 16)
  - Departmental files, 1920s - 1970s: A - C (Box 16)
  - Departmental files, 1920s - 1970s: D - Po (Box 17)
  - Selected personnel files [RESTRICTED] (Box 18)
  - Funding files (Box 18)
  - General files (Box 18)
  - Wm O. Jones: Amer. Agricultural Policy (Box 19)
  - Departmental files, 1920s - 1970s: Pu - W (Box 20)
  - Wm O. Jones: Amer. Agricultural Policy (Box 21)
  - Funding files - gifts, grants (Box 21)
  - Funding files - gifts, grants (Box 22)
  - Funding files - gifts, grants (Box 23)
  - Personnel files for Holbrook Working [RESTRICTED] (Box 23)
  - Publications and silver urn (Box 24)
  - Framed photographs:
    - Carl Alsberg, Merrill K. Bennett, Karl Brandt, Joseph S. Davis, Helen C. Farnsworth, Roger W. Gray, Herbert Hoover, Bruce F. Johnston, William O. Jones, Dudley Kirk, S. Daniel Neumark, E. Louise Peffer, Alonzo E. Taylor, Vladimir P. Timoshenko, Vernon D. Wickizer, Ray Lyman Wilbur, Holbrook Working, and Andrew Carnegie [actually photo of a painting] (Box 25)
  - The following are individual oversized items marked as boxes:
    - Framed photograph and text re Arthur C. Oppenheimer (Box 26)
    - Framed diplomatic passport of Alonzo E. Taylor, 1917 (Box 27)
    - Framed special passport of Alonzo E. Taylor, 1916 (Box 28)